<xml>

<room>
    <handle>start</handle>
    <name>The Fallen Threshold</name>
    <view>
    Rock and dirt debris fill most of the room and what stones are left
    of the walls twist and jut -- eager to finish the collapse.  To the north,
    an arched, stone stairwell descends into darkness.
    </view>
    <exit><way>north</way><to>stairs</to></exit>
</room>


<room>
    <handle>stairs</handle>
    <name>The Crypt Stairwell</name>
    <view>
    A narrow, sharply sloping passage lined with dark granite stairs.  They
    certainly believe in burying their dead down deep. 
    </view>
    <exit><way>south</way><to>start</to></exit>
    <exit><way>north</way><to>landing</to></exit>
</room>

<room>
    <handle>landing</handle>
    <name>The Stone Landing</name>
    <view>
    Inset into the floor is a great marble slab bearing the Stathiz family
    crest.  The slab shows chips and chisel marks where someone failed to
    dislodge it.  In fact, the entire floor is scuffed and scarred.  To the
    south, an arched stairwell leads upward and short halls open to chambers
    both east and west. 
    </view>
    <exit><way>south</way><to>stairs</to></exit>
    <exit><way>east</way><to>upper_chamber</to></exit>
    <exit><way>west</way><to>chapel</to></exit>
</room>

<room>
    <handle>upper_chamber</handle>
    <name>The Upper Chamber</name>
    <view>
    The walls of this chamber are lined with burial shelves but the sealing
    stones have been ripped away and taken.  Gone too are all signs of coffins.
    Only the bones of the dead remain, robbed of all jewelry, preserved 
    clothing, and even buttons. 

    Five wide stairs split the room into a sunken chamber to the north and an
    archway leads to the west.  
    </view>
    <exit><way>north</way><to>lower_chamber</to></exit>
    <exit><way>west</way><to>landing</to></exit>
</room>

<room>
    <handle>lower_chamber</handle>
    <name>The Lower Chamber</name>
    <view>
    Sharing the same vaulted ceiling as the upper chamber, this sunken end
    is smaller and devoid of shelves.  A ponderous, iron door that once sealed
    an opening to west lays tumbled unto the floor.  Clearly, the robbers
    spent countless hours chipping deep sockets in the granite wall to dislodge
    its mighty hinges.   

    In addition to the violated entrance to the east, a hallway leads north and
    a short series of steps lead upward to the south.     
    </view>
    <exit><way>east</way><to>vault</to></exit>
    <exit><way>north</way><to>ossuary</to></exit>
    <exit><way>south</way><to>upper_chamber</to></exit>
</room>

<room>
    <handle>vault</handle>
    <name>Vault of the Matriarch</name>
    <view>
    Lady Evefen Stathiz, august matriarch of the clan, has certainly seen
    better days.  Her mouldering bones lay scattered in several heaps.  The
    massive, marble sarcophagus that once guarded her rest has been dumped on
    its side and, strangely, dragged towards the entrance of the chamber.

    Most of the room's marble tile has been pilfered as well as lamp sconces
    and various metal fixtures.

    There is a doorway missing a door to the west.
    </view>
    <exit><way>west</way><to>lower_chamber</to></exit>
</room>


</xml>
